Kentucky Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty; Records apap401
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Kentucky Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Records
1965-2022
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap401
2.26 cubic ft.
42.1 GB
This collection documents the lobbying and advocacy efforts of the Kentucky Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (KCADP) in its endeavor to end the use of capital punishment in the state of Kentucky.
Content Description
This collection of the Kentucky Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (KCADP) includes digital and physical files: correspondence, administrative records (founding documents, meeting minutes, financial reports), newsclippings, court documents, communication and outreach materials, newsletters, subject files, case files, legislative activities, and video.
This collection contains multiple file types of the advocacy videos that were used by the KCADP on social media. Alternate files types can be accessed via request.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
All items in this collection were donated by Pat Delahanty in 2022.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is made up of ten series, each arranged chronologically.
Historical Note
The Kentucky Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (KCADP) seeks to end capital punishment in Kentucky through education, outreach, coalition-building, and grassroots organizing.
The KCADP has its roots in two other organizations - the Louisville chapter of the Southern Coalition on Jails and Prisons, established in 1976 and which thrived for about a decade, and the Kentucky Civil Liberties Union which provided an organizing foundation for the KCADP beginning in 1984.
A state steering committee formed in 1986, the KCADP began to distribute newsletters in 1987, and the organization was formally incorporated in 1988.
In 1996, the KCADP put forward a "Racial Justice Act" bill that passed at the House of Representatives but failed at the Senate. It was reproposed in 1998 and passed as Senate Bill 171.
The KCADP applied for the Death Penalty Mobilization Fund (DPMF) Grants from the combined Tides Foundation and The Advocacy Fund from the years of 2009-2014, 2016, 2017, 2021, and 2022.
KCADP also partnered with organizations including the American Bar Association, the American Law Institute, Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty, the Kentucky Innocence Project, the Knights of Columbus, Murder Victim Families of Kentucky, and Witness to Innocence to further their collective abolishment goals. KCADP also worked in collaboration with Sister Helen Prejean, a leading advocate in the United States for the abolition of the death penalty by hosting events for Sister Helen to speak on her book and her work as an abolitionist.
Separated Materials
The archivist transferred the books: "Politics Religion and Death: Memoir of a Lobbyist" and "The Second Grave: A Case for the Abolition of the Death Penalty" both by Carl Wedekind to the book division of Special Collections. They were cataloged and included in the University Library Catalog.
Kentucky Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty; Capital punishment--Kentucky; Death Penalty; Capital punishment; Capital punishment--Kentucky; Capital punishment--Law and legislation; Capital punishment -- Law and legislation -- United States -- History.; Capital punishment--Political aspects.; Capital punishment -- United States; Capital punishment--United States--Cases; Capital punishment--United States--History; Discrimination in capital punishment--United States; Correspondence; Criminal court records; Legal documents; Newspapers
- Advocacy Efforts, 1989- 2021; 2001-2021
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains videos (in various digital formats) that were created for social media to advocate for the abolishment of the death penalty, a call campaign to legislators, documents surrounding tabling at the Kentucky State Fair, polling efforts and results, and testimonies.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged into seven subseries.
  - Planning Documents, 2003-2016
    - University of Louisville Law School Diversity Presentation, 2003 April 7
    - KCADP Membership Sign Up Form, 2012 July 24
    - List of Persons Sentenced to Life in Prison for Aggravated Murder During a Period Beginning in May 2010, 2011
    - Sister Helen Perjean Fall Schedule, 2012
    - KCADP Sign Up Form For New Members, 2014
    - Southeast Kentucky Chamber of Commerce Hillbilly Days Application, 2016
  - Advocacy Videos
    This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Wendell Berry- "Wendell Berry", 2009 February 28; 2020 September 28
    - Ben Griffith- "One Terrible Day", 2009 April 24; 2021 August 3
    - Amanda Bragg- "A Very Personal Journey", 2009 April 24
    - Chris Beckett - "They Do Change", 2009 April 27; 2020 May 8
    - Russlyn Case-Compton- "We Kill Real People", 2009 April 28; 2020 July 1
    - Mary Alice Pratt- "Something You Never Get Over", 2009 April 29; 2021 April 23
    - Carrie Summers - "Is it A Good Idea", 2009 May 5; 2020 June 22
    - Courtney Boyd, 2009 May 5; 2020 July 15
    - Georgetown Professors - "To Speak Good News", 2009 May 5; 2021 March 6
    - Eugene Thomas - "And It's Madness", 2009 May 12; 2021 September 4
    - Keith McKenzie- "As I Grew Deeper in My Faith", 2009 May 12; 2021 May 9
    - Dr. Frances Weinstock, 2009 May 13; 2021 February 16
    - Father John Rausch- "Victims of Violence", 2009 May 13; 2021 March 9
    - Vickie Cox - "The Love We Had For Him", 2009 May 26; 2021 March 16
    - Willow Rouben- "No Justice in Killing Another", 2009 June 2; 2021 October 13
    - John Stopher- "I Would Appreciate Your Help", 2009 June 20; 2021 March 24
    - Donna Stopher- "I'm Just Sorry", 2009 June 23; 2021 January 30
    - Marjory Grieshop- "The Death Penalty Destroys Compassion", 2009 July 8; 2021 March 9
    - Video Interviews from HillbillyDays, 2009 July 8
    - Voices from Harlan, 2009 July 8; 2020 September 22
    - Sharon Colton- "Why Do We Kill People", 2009 July 11; 2021 July 30
    - Attica Scott - "If Our System of Justice is Working", 2009 August 22; 2020 May 1
    - Bert Mutersbaugh- "So Many False Convictions", 2009 October 2; 2021 June 22
    - Mary Lou Houck- "The Death Penalty Has Failed", 2009 October 18; 2021 May 7
    - Galli - "Not in My Name", 2009 November 1; 2021 March 1
    - Mary Catherine Rademaker- "Not Only Do No Harm", 2009 November 1; 2021 May 5
    - Paul Simmons- "Which of You is Without Sin", 2009 November 1; 2021 July 11
    - Stew Schneider- "I Wondered Where Jesus Would Be Standing", 2009 November 1; 2021 August 3
    - Helen Prejean - "An Invitation from Sr. Helen Prejean", 2009 November 15; 2021 March 11
    - Tom Spalding, 2009 November 15; 2020 September 30
    - Ray Larson, 2009 November 15
    - Foley Family - "Got a Son in the Death House", 2009 November 24; 2021 February 25
    - Bill Deatheridge, 2009 December 8; 2020 August 4
    - Joyce Frazier- "She was Strangled and Beaten", 2009 December 20; 2021 April 3
    - Erin Kennedy - "Kinda Like Cussing", 2009 December 26; 2021 February 23
    - Closing Prayer NCADP 2010 Louisville Celebration, 2010 January 17
    - Dolores Delahanty- "But I Won the Election", 2010 January 23; 2020 September 26
    - Margie Stelzer- "A Life of Non-Violence", 2010 February 13
    - Al Bennett, 2010 February 21; 2020 May 14
    - Father Dick Sullivan, 2010 March 14; 2020 September 24
    - Mary Margaret Mulvihill- "Capital Punishment Needs to End Now", 2010 March 23; 2021 June 10
    - Sarah Honaker- "Scared By It", 2010 April 5; 2021 March 15
    - George Edwards, 2010 April 6
    - Theresa Hoffman- "Forgiveness is Very Healing", 2010 April 26; 2021 August 6
    - Andy Yates- "It's so Easy to Make a Mistake", 2010 May 11; 2021 April 14
    - Arishiya Saiyed- "If Something Were That Flawed", 2010 May 15; 2020 May 6
    - Marsha Willoughby - "You See a Monster", 2010 May 17; 2021 April 17
    - Chase Parker- "I Am a Christian", 2010 June 8; 2020 July 9
    - Marian McClure Taylor- "No Boundaries on God's Love", 2010 July 10; 2021 April 15
    - Miguel Lagunas- "Modern Nations Do Not Use the Death Penalty", 2010 July 18; 2021 May 11
    - Loretta Baisden, 2010 September 25; 2021 April 8
    - Eric Mount- "Death Penalty Alphabet", 2010 September 27; 2020 October 16
    - Ollie Barber, 2010 September 27; 2021 June 24
    - Mallori Puchino- "I Grew Up in the Bible Belt", 2010 October 6
    - Jane Chiles- "Murdered ikn Cold Blood", 2012 August 13
    - Katherine Gaines- "Stand Before the Almighty", 2012 August 13
    - Rita Shoulders- "To Honor Mildred", 2012 August 13
    - Sabrina Butler- "Innocent", 2013 November 25; 2019 June 23
    - Miriam Hans- "It Shows Value Reflections", 2015 May 9
    - Lawmakers in Nebraska Abolish The Death Penalty, 2015 May 27
    - Jeanie Watts- "No Right to Take a Life", 2015 October 20; 2021 March 20
    - Peter Houck- "There Only to Listen Not to Condemn", 2015 December 9; 2021 July 21
    - Hillbilly Days, 2017 April 21
    - Edwin Chandler- "Edwin Chandler An Innocent Man", 2017 June 17
    - Ruth Lowe- "I Had A Brother", 2018 April 11; 2020 April 26
    - Mike VonAllmen- "He Was Innocent", 2019 September 10; 2021 July 17
    - Dorothy Schuette- "Many Have Said How Sorry They Are", 2021 February 6
    - Abolition gifs, 2021 June 13
    - Message to KY Legislators Regarding History of Lynching in Their County, 2021 June 23
    - Ray Schweri- "A Changed Person", 2021 July 28
    - Miriam Byrd, 2021 December 24
    - Children of the Same God Video, 2011
    - Old Ending Credits, 2009-2010
    - Video Common Assets-Instagram, 2012-2021
  - Call Campaign
    - Bart Rowloand Call Campaign, 2019
    - Call Campaign-03 Bridges, 2019
    - Call Campaign-05 Imes, 2019
    - Call Campaign-06 Freeland, 2019
    - Call Campaign-08 Walker, 2019
    - Call Campaign-11 Wiederstein, 2019
    - Call Campaign-14 Lewis, 2019
    - Call Campaign-23 Riley, 2019
    - Call Campaign-24 Reed, 2019
    - Call Campaign-27 Webber, 2019
    - Call Campaign-32 Bojanowski, 2019
    - Call Campaign-66 Massey, 2019
    - Chris Freland Benton Call Campaign, 2019
    - House 004 Call Campaign-KCADP, 2019
    - House 008 Call Campaign-KCADP, 2019
    - House 016 Call Campaign-KCADP, 2019
    - House 017 Call Campaign-KCADP, 2019
    - House 021 Call Campaign-KCADP, 2019
    - House 039 Call Campaign-KCADP, 2019
    - House 061 Call Campaign-KCADP, 2019
    - House 062 Call Campaign-KCADP, 2019
    - House 2019 Call Campaign
    - Jason Petrie Call Campaign, 2019
    - Lynn Belecher Marion Call Campaign, 2019
    - Phillip Pratt Call Campaign, 2019
    - Savannah Maddox Call Campaign, 2019
    - Steve Sheldon Call Campaign, 2019
  - Kentucky State Fair
    - Wendell Berry Graphic, 2009 January 23
    - Wendell Berry Poster, 2009 January 23
    - Call Legislators Graphic Photograph, 2012 August 8
    - Wendell Berry Poster, Web Version, 2012 August 8
    - Call Legislators Graphic Photograph, Web Version, 2012 August 8
    - Registration Form to Work at State Fair Booth, 2012 August 14
    - Registration Form to Work at State Fair Booth, 2012 August 16
    - KCADP Booth Photograph, 2012 August 17
    - Registration Form to Work at State Fair Booth, 2012 August 18
    - 2012 State Fair File Showing Time Slots Taken, 2012 August 18-2012 August 26
    - 2013 State Fair File Showing Time Slots Taken, with notes, 2012 August 18-2012 August 26
    - Hillbilly Days Vendor Contract, 2017 April 6
    - Kentucky State Fair Fern Service Kit, 2017 August 10
    - Kentucky State Fair Exhibitor and Concessionaire, 2017 August 17-2017 August 27
    - Kentucky State Fair Application for Inside Commercial Exhibit Space, 2017 August 17-2017 August 27
    - KCADP Palm Card, Victim, 2018 June 7
    - KCADP Poster, Victim, 2018 June 7
    - Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Poster, 2018 June 7
    - KCADP Palm Card, Innocence, 2018 June 7
    - KCADP Poster, Innocence, 2018 June 7
    - Court Days Schedule, 2018 September 24
    - State Fair Talking Points, 2011 August
    - Security Badge and Promotional Prize Forms, 2012 August
    - Postcard to Chairman Tilley, 2011
    - Postcard to Chairman Jensen, 2011
    - Copy of KY State Fair Petition Signers with Emails, 2011
    - State Fair Informational Packet, 2013
    - Summer Death Penalty Tour Work Plan, 2013
    - Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Logo, 2013
    - Kentucky Murder Victim Families Who Oppose The Death Penalty graphic, 2013
    - Murder Victims' Family Members- No Need to Kill Poster, 2013
    - Postcard Inviting to Visit the KCADP YouTube Channel, Side 1, 2013
    - Postcard Inviting to Visit the KCADP YouTube Channel, Side 2, 2013
    - State Fair Sample Volunteer Schedule, 2013
    - KCADP State Fair Timeline, 2013
    - State Fair Organizational Volunteer List, 2013
    - Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Innocence Flyer, Black and White, 2014
    - Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Public Safety Flyer, Black and White, 2014
    - Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Victims Flyer, Black and White, 2014
    - Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Overview Bullets Flyer, Black and White, 2014
    - Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Cost Flyer, Black and White, 2014
    - Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Fairness Flyer, Black and White, 2014
    - "Worst of the Worst: Cases Within the Last 5 years that Qualified for the Death Penalty but Resulted in Lesser Sentences", 2014
    - Kentucky Wrongful Convictions, 2014
    - Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Palm Card, Print Quality, Three Quotes, 2014
    - Kentucky Repeal Banner, 2014
    - Kentucky State Fair Space Contract, 2015
    - Kentucky State Fair Space Contract, 2016
    - State Fair Support Document, 2016
    - Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Palm Card, Print Quality, Two Quotes, 2017
    - Pamphlet from both KCADP and Victims' Family Members, 2017
    - Innocence Page 1, 2017
    - Innocence Page 2, 2017
    - Victims' Family Members Page 1, 2017
    - Victims' Family Members Page 2, 2017
    - Application for Court Day Vendors, 2017
    - KCADP Contact Card, 2017
    - KY State Fair Sign Ups, 2018
  - Polling
    - Complete Poll Script for Kentucky Residents, 2016 May 4
    - Kentucky Poll Results, 2016 May 9
    - Kentucky Poll Results from Ron Langley, 2016 June 16
    - Letter from Ronald E. Langley Regarding the 2016 Kentucky Survey, 2016 June 27
    - Draft 1 of Poll Press Release, 2016 July 3
    - Kentucky Death Penalty Poll Results, 2016 July 10
    - Press Release of Poll Results, Final Version, 2016 July 26
    - Press Release of Poll Results, Op-Ed, 2016 July 29
    - Email RE: Google Alert- Kentucky Death Penalty, 2016 August 2
    - "The Death Penalty in Kentucky: Changing Attitudes" Document, With Recent Poll Results, 2016 August 8
    - "The Advocate" Journal of Criminal Justice Education & Research Vol. 29, No. 1, 2007 January
    - "2006 Statewide Poll Shows Kentuckians Overwhelmingly Reject Death Penalty" Excerpt from The Advocate, 2007 January
    - Death Penalty Polling Questions, Draft, 2013 June
    - Poll Results Press Results, Draft, 2016 July
    - "The Death Penalty in Kentucky: Changing Attitudes" Brief, With Recent Poll Results, 2016 August
    - Death Penalty Proposed Polling Questions, 2015
    - Kentucky Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers Call for Moratorium, 2016
    - "What Kentuckians Say About the Death Penalty" Infographic, 2016
    - Innocence Concerns Graphic, 2016
    - Replace Death Penalty With Life Without Parole Graphic, 2016
    - High Cost Concerns Graphic, 2016
    - Moratorium by Govenor Graphic, 2016
    - Long Prison Sentence Over Death Penalty, 2016
    - Death Penalty Attitudes in Kentucky, 1989-2016
  - Rallies
    - Rally Against the Death Penalty, Frankfort, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rallies-Articles, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Rally for Recovery Flyer, 2009
  - Surveys and Polls
    - KCADP Surveys and Polls and Comparison Survey and Polls (1/2), 1989-2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - KCADP Surveys and Polls and Comparison Survey and Polls (2/2), 1989-2006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Testimonies
    - Testimony of Jane J. Chiles, Executive Director, 2001 October 16
    - "Jail House Snitch Testimony-NC Case", 2003 November 5
    - John Chambers Testimony, 2007
    - Nancy Rowles Testimony at House Judiciary Committee Meeting, 2007 February 26
    - Carol Heilman Testimony at House Judiciary Committee Meeting, 2007 February 26
- Communications and Outreach, 1972-2015
  This series contains documents from the courier-journal project, emaiol communications, Kentucky Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (KCADP) mailing lists and press contacts, memos, physical and born digital news articles for state and nationwide newspapers/journals, KCADP newsletters, postcards, press releases, and public news service usage reports.
  This series is arranged into nine subseries.
  - Draft and Planning Documents, 1987-2015
    - Proposal RE: Communications Plan Initiative to Abolish the Death Penalty, 2014 February 6
    - Guide to Commenting on Kentucky's Proposed Execution Protocols, 2012
    - Draft for Announcement of New Employees, 2021
    - KCADP Planned Outreach, 2015
    - Death Penalty Cartoon, 2008
    - NCADP Sign Up Form for Contact List, 2008
    - Memorandums Regarding Interviews, 1987-1988
  - Letters, 1984-2021
    - Letters, 1984-2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - An Open Letter to Governor George Ryan, 2002 September 15
    - Fall Fundraising Letter for Supporters, 2021 November
    - End of Year Letter, 2008 December 11
  - Mailing List, 2007-2014
    - Petition Sign-Up, 2007 September 28
    - Master List Through September, 2010 September 10
    - KCADP State Fair Names from Contact List, 2011 August 30
    - Contatcs from St. Michael's, 2012 September 15
    - KCADP Membership List - Louisville Only, 2012 December 19
    - KCADP Master Membership List, 2013 January 17
    - KCADP Master Membership List, 2013 April 30
    - KCADP Master Membership List with Donation Amounts, 2013 April 30
    - KY Council of Churches Database, 2013 November 22
    - KCC for Invite to Sister Helen Prejean Event, 2013 November 22
    - Press Contacts List, 2014 January 25
    - Constant Contact Master List, 2014 August 16
    - INSIGHTBB Constant Contact List, 2014 August 16
    - Brockman Fundraising List, 2012 September
    - Drinkard Complete List, 2014 September
    - Mailing List for Physical Mailing, 2014 October
    - Members List with Senator and Representative Names, 2009
    - Total State Fair Contact Sign-Ups, 2012
    - List of Contributors Over $100, 2013
    - Constant Contact State Fair Contact Sign-Ups, 2014
    - Total State Fair Contact Sign-Ups, 2014
    - Total World Fest Contact Sign-Ups, 2014
    - Working Addresses Document, 2014
  - News Articles, 1986-2017
    - Al Cross Article on Doctor Fletcher, 2005 October 2
    - Article "2 Plead Guilty to Murder, Hiding Body", 2004 April 30
    - Article "Another Retired Florida Judge calls for Abolition", 2003 February 16
    - Article Clipping "Death Penalty Denies Hope For a Prisoner's Conversion", 2014 December 14
    - "Death Penalty Remains Unfair, Arbitrary: It's Time to Abolish Capital Punishment", 2011
    - Articles, misc, 1986-2016 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Articles, misc, 1986-2016 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - News Article "The 8 Great Worries of the World, as Seen by John Paul II Attacks on Life, Family, Environment Among the Concerns", 2002 August 31
    - Courier Journal Article "Deadly Injustice", 2007 June 4
    - Kentucky.Com "A Path to Healing, But Not Legislation", 2007 July 1
    - Tennessean.com Article "Events Have Raised Doubts About Fairness in System", 2007 October 15
    - Courier Journal "Departing Gov. Fletcher Pardons 83", 2007 December 11
    - Kentucky.com Article "100 Get Pardons, Commutations", 2007 December 11
    - The Torch Article "The Next Big Step to Abolish the Death Penalty", 2008 September 28
    - Wrongful Convictions Article "Man's Conviction Set Aside in 1993 Shooting Death", 2009 October 15
    - The Record Article "Death Penalty Put 'On Trial' By New Video Effort", 2009 October 22
    - Death Penalty Information Center Editorial "A Decade of Progress on Death Penalty Justice", 2009 December 24
    - Death Penalty Information Center Editorial "Outlaw Death Penalty to Save Lives and Cash", 2010 November 11
    - Death Penalty Focus Article "Theologian Dale Recinella Responds to Biblical Justification of Death Penalty", 2011 March 29
    - Op-Ed "Death Penalty Remains Unfair, Arbitrary: It's Time to Abolish Capital Punishment", 2011 June 29
    - Kentucky.com Article "Time to End Kentucky's Death Penalty", 2011 July 3
    - The Record Article "Four Women Work Against Death Penalty", 2011 July 28
    - Collection of The Record Articles, 2011 July 28
    - The Record Article "Women Cling to Faith Despite Tragedy", 2011 August 4
    - The Record Editorial "End the Death Penalty", 2011 December 15
    - WDRB.com Article "Man Falsely Convicted of Murder to be Paid $8.5 Million", 2012 October 5; 2012 October 9
    - Kentucky.com Op-Ed "Abandon Executions: Death Penalty Unfair, Illogical and Costly", 2012 December 3
    - Community Challenge Article "Crime Victims Deserve Support", 2013 April 22
    - Chicago Sun-Times.com Article "Illionois Owes This Man an Apology", 2013 July 18; 2013 July 19
    - Kentucky New Era Article "Exonerated Death Row Inmate Speaks to Abolish Capital Punishment in Kentucky", 2013 August 5
    - Mtairynews.com Article "Opposition Growing to End Death Penalty in KY", 2013 August 13
    - Messenger-Inquirer "Former Death Row Inmate Blasts System", 2013 October 15
    - Daily News Article "Copass Gets Life in Prison", 2014 August 20
    - The Kentucky Standard Article "Priest: Kentucky Close to Abolishing Death Penalty", 2014 September 23
    - WKMS.Org News Article "Priest Thinks Kentucky Could Be Next Southern State to Abolish Death Penalty", 2014 September 25
    - KY Standard Article "Death Penalty Should be Done Away With", 2014 September 27
    - Courier Journal "Ault: Why I'm Against the Death Penalty", 2014 October 8
    - Op-Ed Draft "The death penalty in Kentucky: broken beyond repair", 2014 December 2
    - Courier Journal Article "Woman Please Guilt to Murdering Grandmother", 2014 December 16
    - Kentucky.com Op-Ed "Life Sentence Simpler, Cheaper Than Education", 2014 December 21
    - Louisville Courier Journal Article "Replace the Death Penalty with Life Without Parole", 2014 December 26
    - Courier Journal Article "Replace the Death Penalty With Life Without Parole", 2014 December 28
    - Kentucky.com Article "Fayette Circuit Judge: 'The Death Penalty Probably Should Not Be a Penalty, Ever'", 2015 January 8
    - Courier Journal Article "Father is Indicted for Baby's Death", 2015 January 9
    - Central Kentucky News Article "Prosecutors May Seek Death Penalty in Apartment Shooting Case", 2015 March 20
    - Op-Ed for The Record- Tinkering, 2015 April 6
    - Kentucky New Era. Vol. 130, No. 93 Article "Is the Death Penalty a Failing System?", 2017 March 27-2017 March 28
    - Kentucky New Era. Vol. 130, No. 94 Article "Death Penalty Comes With High Price Tag", 2017 March 29
    - Kentucky New Era. Vol. 130, No. 96 Article "Death Penalty Not a Partisan Issue", 2017 March 31
    - CMN Article, 2012 January
    - CMN Catholic Church of Kentuckly Article, 2012 January
    - Baptist Article on Texas Moratorium, 2003
    - Philly.com Editorial "PA.'s Death Penalty", 2007
    - CMN Article "Putting the Death Penalty on Trial in Kentucky", 2011
    - Louisville Courier Journal Article "DNA Testing May Clear Two in Alleged 'Satanic' Murder", 2015